Hello everyone, thanks for participating in CLO Virtual User Summit.
I am Ying, Business Director at CLO Shanghai office.
I'm so glad to have one of our CLO's clients today with us, Ms. Emerald.
She joined Kmart in October 2020 as 3D manager running the 3D team and working in Project SQUARE to drive end-to-end digital transformation.
Thank you for joining us and we cannot wait to see your presentation.
Okay, let's start.
It's a pleasure to be here sharing some stories about our 3D journey.
So, first of all, let me introduce our brand.
Kmart Australia is established in 1969, operating more than 326 stores throughout Australia and New Zealand.
Let's where our 3D project are from.
Our 3D exploration is a bit special.
Instead of starting from a functional team, we launched a specialized project squad to drive our digital transformation.
Currently, we have got 10 team members.
In the squad, based in three regions, originating six key functions in apparel industry.
This project started from scratch in October of 2020.
And we made software decision at end of June last year after a series of trial and consideration from different aspects.
Then to now, we have completed two seasons end-to-end developments with the pilot department.
We have seen a great benefit from 3D.
And the whole company are getting more and more excited to this new way of working.
All this success thanks to efforts and passion from the whole team and inputs from our stakeholders.
Here, I would like to share something I heard from the Chinese media recently.
There are so many answers in the world waiting for good questions.
I found it's especially insensitive when we are talking about 3D exploration.
The most important thing is that the world is full of unknown.
In the industry, there are already so many good resources.
And we have got really great concept.
And we have got amazing technologies and talented users.
So these are all will support our digital revolution.
But on the other hand, at least in each start, we are facing different choices.
All these choices form different ways for future.
It will make a difference if we all start from the good questions.
Here, I would like to share some important questions and choices we have made.
And these represent for where we are and who we are.
So the first question is, which products shall we start with?
Easy starts or the difficult starts?
Have to be realistic like we can't start everything at once, right?
We'd better begin with a small group.
Create a small success and then scale up once we have got more certainty.
If not talking about artists, but from the commercial consideration.
Of course, the life will be less tough if we start from the easy styles.
Such as T-shirts or shirts, which are with simple construction, consistent body shapes and fabrics.
And also with the larger volume of productions, which can prove the benefits in the most obvious way.
But after overall consideration, we made a crazy decision in the opposite.
To start from the difficult styles.
As we are aiming to expose more issues at the early stage.
And when we can get more prepared.
And also we can learn from the failure when we can afford to.
In this way, we can get more prepared before we scale into the larger scope.
When we define the difficult styles,
we consider variation from both styling and fabric.
The more variable fabric it is,
there will be more handlings to consider for both draping and also the appearance.
And then the more diverse styling is,
there will be more construction to start in the digital world.
These two factors actually will multiply the different difficulties.
And going through all our categories,
we finally chose to start from the women's fashion world.
And I just want to say,
we have worked with many different styles,
as it represents for the most complex case for both.
It almost killed us at the beginning.
We must satisfy the biggest eyes of the development team.
And we have to borrow with the more workload at starting point.
We have to overcome the challenges from different styling features day by day.
And also have to train the 3D users with both software handling skills,
as well as the pattern and garment construction knowledge.
Also,
we need good resources on the fabric.
the resources on the fabric digitization i feel so proud of the team that we have finally made it
and thanks to clove for supporting all of these also master say without backing from the management
we can't be so great taking this decision working with so many challenges by constantly touching the
boundary then breaking the boundary our progress over the past six months has been remarkable
since we have made a 3d decision last season our first sample approval rate of this department
broke the record by seven percent and we have also got significant lead time reduction
these are the most challenging products with easier products there will be more space to win
and since we have got these tricky products under control there will be few product types
to worry about in the future and the second question here is
what's our desire to 3d operating model in other words how do we plan to use 3d
shall we just use 3d simulation in the prototyping or are we prepared for the digital transformation
changing the rule of developing game our choice is the second we want to change the way of working
based on the trust of 3d instead of making it disconnected from the development with dots
which means we have to
make prototyping happen in 3d world and we are able to do fitting and rich review in the virtual world
to support this decision the first step is to make 3d realistic we must gain the confidence
from stakeholders against 3d so that they are happy to replace most physical samples in development
starting from the fabric we need to use the correct quality for digitalization and we should validate fabric to
to achieve desired accuracy before using them onto 3D samples.
Then consistent address forms are also important. We are able to get a twin set avatar in 3D.
The correct 3D pattern is also important. Pattern used for 3D and pattern used for physical sampling
will be a bit different. And also, when exporting patterns from 3D for physical sampling,
actually different users might work in different ways.
We must ensure the input and output patterns of 3D speak the same language
by setting up the standard 3D pattern criteria and build up the tracking process.
And we have also gradually realized how important it is
to apply the suitable constructions to the 3D sample.
And last but not least, other 3D-related knowledge needs to be refreshed with learning
through the correlation.
We must agree,
in current stage, 3D can't replace all of the physical samples. It can replace some,
but it can't replace more. Correlation can give us more ideas on handling improvements,
fabric accuracy, and notice the technical limitation, if there's any.
With least learnings, the asset library and handling standards can be adjusted accordingly.
Also, based on which, we can set up realistic expectations to the 3D samples.
Instead of just getting lost in all these technical issues.
The third question here is, what's the ambition of our 3D journey?
Technology-focused or the whole game?
Further thinking from the previous question, there's no doubt here that we choose to play
the whole game. We need to roll out the digital transformation in different aspects with different
parties in order.
To win the whole game.
Good 3D users are fundamental. The user skills will decide how far can we go.
We need to find the desired skill size for the 3D users in different scenarios.
And then we need to get better visibility about skill map of in-house and suppliers.
Then make a proper upscaling plan.
Also, we need to consider the role revolutions.
There are already different roles in the traditional way of working, and there might be some
new roles generated in the industry with specialized focus.
There's a funny story like I posted a role of 3D merchandiser, and it took us five months to get a
suitable person. Because many people have no idea about what it is, and they're still doubting if it
is a real role. Also, the 3D prototyping process is also important. When we invite people to join
the new game, we have to set up a clear agenda.
We have to make sure that we have a clear and realistic role, so that everybody is happy to play.
And how do we ensure a more streamlined development life cycle? We rely on system integration.
We still got a lot to do based on all these considerations, and all of us are confident
and excited about a bigger, a brighter future.
The last question to share today is how do we move forward? Faster alone or further together?
Well, I think we can make a decision and move faster within a smaller group, but it might be
risky if we just take our own opinions in the journey industry, which might end up with some
buy-offs. So we definitely choose to go further together, embrace small collaborations.
In-house team members, suppliers, software companies, and other partners in the industry all
play key roles in this new world.
It's necessary to be open-minded, and it's worth it to share resources and information with each
other. Then we can get input and feedback in order to adjust the direction in line with the
industry trends. None of us can be quite sure about the future, but by working together,
we can definitely get more possibilities. I really feel these forums are quite meaningful,
which are great platforms to share information with each other. Thank you again for inviting.
I'm looking forward to a brighter future in the digital world with all of you. Thanks.